One of the most exciting developments
in deep learning has been
the transformer Network, or
sometimes called Transformers.
This is an architecture that has
completely taken the NLP world by storm.
And many of the most effective algorithms for
NLP today are based on
the transformer architecture.
It is a relatively complex neural
network architecture, but in this and
the next three videos after this
will go through it piece by piece.
So that by the end of this next four
videos, you have a good sense of how
the transformer Network works and
you'll be able to apply to your problems.
As the complexity of your
sequence task increases,
so does the complexity of your model.
We have started this
course with the RNN and
found that it had some problems
with vanishing gradients,
which made it hard to capture long
range dependencies and sequences.
We then looked at the GRU and then
the LSTM model as a way to resolve many
of those problems where you make use of
gates to control the flow of information.
And so each of these units
had a few more computations.
While these editions improved control
over the flow of information,
they also came with increased complexity.
So as we move from our RNNs to GRU to
LSTM ,the models became more complex.
And all of these models
are still sequential models in
that they ingested the input,
maybe the input sentence one word or
one token at the time.
And so, as as if each unit was like
a bottleneck to the flow of information.
Because to compute the output
of this final unit, for example,
you first have to compute the outputs
of all of the units that come before.
In this video, you learned about the
transformer architecture, which allows you
to run a lot more of these computations
for an entire sequence in parallel.
So you can ingest an entire
sentence all at the same time,
rather than just processing it one
word at a time from left to right.
The Transformer Network was published
in a seminal paper by Ashish Vaswani
, Noam Shazeer, Niki Parmar,
Jakob Uszkoreit, Llion Jones,
Aidan Gomez, Lukasz Kaiser and Illia Polosukhin.
One of the inventors of
the Transformer network, Lukasz Kaiser,
is also co instructor of the NLP
specialization with deep learning dot AI.
So you can check that out as well when
you're done with this deep learning
specialization.
The major innovation of
the transformer architecture is
combining the use of attention
based representations and
a CNN convolutional neural
network style of processing.
So an RNN may process
one output at the time,
and so maybe y(0) feeds in to
them that you compute y(1) and
then this is used to compute y(2).
This is a very sequential
way of processing tokens,
and you might contrast this with a CNN or
confident that can take
input a lot of pixels.
Yeah, or maybe a lot of words and
can compute representations for
them in parallel.
So what you see in the Attention Network
is a way of computing very rich,
very useful representations of words.
But with something more akin to this
CNN style of parallel processing.
To understand the attention network,
there will be two key ideas will
go through in the next few videos.
The first is self attention.
The goal of self attention is,
if you have, say,
a sentence of five words will end up
computing five representations for
these five words,
was going to write A1,A2,A3, A4 and A5.
And this will be an attention based
way of computing representations for
all the words in your
sentence in parallel.
Then multi headed attention is basically for
loop over the self attention process.
So you end up with multiple
versions of these representations.
And it turns out that
these representations,
which will be very rich representations,
can be used for
machine translation or
other NLP tasks to great effectiveness.
So in the next video, let's jump
in to learn about self attention,
to compute these rich representations.
The video after that,
we'll talk about multi headed attention.
And then the final video on transforming
networks will put all of these together so
that you understand how the entire
transformer architecture works into end.
Let's go to the next video.